# PIETRO ARAMBURÚ GALLARDO

Advanced English – Intermediate Portuguese – Intermediate Italian

PietroMauricioAg@outlook.com +51951613233

#### **SUMMARY**

I started programming when I was 6 years old making games, currently I have 5 years as a software engineer and 7 years as a Web Dev. Lately I'm getting more interested in web development. I specialize in React, React-Native, Node.js, MongoDB, Next.Js and Python. Currently I'm looking to integrate AI with web. I have 159 IQ and I like to learn and teach.

# **EXPERIENCE**

**Xbox Game Studios** 2022 – 2023

**Cloud Operations** 

Leverage the power of cloud operations to improve game scalability and availability.

- Integration with Microsoft Azure cloud services for data storage and processing.
- Implementation of cloud operations technologies, using containers and Kubernetes, to improve scalability and availability.
- Testing and debugging with the Xbox Development Kit to ensure optimal performance.

**Blackrock** 2022 – 2022

Code Refactoring - Web Development.

Help design and build the world's next generation technology platform.

- Building UI components for portfolio risk calculations and portfolio accounting using react.
- Valuation management and investment operations navigation analysis using Python.
- Apply validated quality software engineering practices (SDLC Methodologies test driven development TDD - Unit testing - CI/CD strategies) in all phases of development.
- Ensure resiliency and stability through quality code reviews, unit, regression and user acceptance testing, development operations and level two production support.

**Uayki** 2021 – 2022

Web / Mobile Development - Video Game Development.

Development of applications for the benefit of those most in need.

- Development of an education service, it contains a library with various topics, audiovisual resources, documents, audio, games, applications, among others... Using AWS, Python and Node.JS with MongoDB & Docker.
- Implementation of random searches, favorite lists, comments, reactions, feedback, searches through filters, creation of profiles and progress tracking using Vue.JS.
- Creation of an educational game, with a more user-friendly user interface and more interactive themes.

- Development of several mini-games inside, learning documents and a high score table.
- I used the Unity engine to develop the game, Python for file compression and programmed all the scripts with C#.

# **Ryzemind** 2020 – 2022

Web / Mobile Development – Artificial Intelligence.

Development of video games and custom software.

- Data analysis to understand user expectations and preferences.
- Design of the user interface and game functionality using React.
- Integration with a MongoDB database for question and answer storage.
- Use of external APIs and Web Scraping together with AI to get questions and answers in different categories. (Python, TensorFlow, Beautiful Soup, Node.Js)
- Development of game sharing functionality by users and creation of categories.
- Implementation of scoring and ranking systems to encourage competition.

#### **Immersive Garden** 2019 – 2020

Web Development - UX - Database.

Creation of an e-commerce platform for an organic products store.

- Design of the e-commerce platform with an intuitive and attractive user experience.
- Development of the platform using Php, Html, Js, CSS and Wp.
- Integration with a MySQL relational database to manage orders, products and customers.
- Implementation of secure and efficient local payment processes (Stripe among others).

#### **Latvia** 2018 – 2019

Web development - Advertising design.

Creation of a virtual reality experience for a tourism company.

- Requirement's analysis to understand the needs and expectations of customers and the company.
- Creation of 3D models of tourist destinations using Blender.
- Integration of the 3D models into a virtual reality experience using Three.js.
- Development of the user interface and functionality of the experience using JavaScript and Node.js.
- Use of advanced CSS to create an engaging and consistent experience.

### **MFN Group** 2017 – 2019

PC / Mobile software development.

Mobile application and web platform for a general services company.

- Web platform design for an intuitive user experience using React and Wp.
- Development of the mobile application using React Native.
- Integration with existing payment and service management systems with PayPal.
- Testing and debugging to ensure optimal performance.
- Use of agile methodologies for an iterative and flexible development process.

**Up!** 2016 – 2017

Analytics - Treatment and data management.

Customer lifecycle analysis and optimization in an online store.

- Collection and cleaning of data from a variety of sources, including transaction records, customer profiles and surveys using SQL.
- Exploratory data analysis to understand customer behavior patterns. Using PowerBI.
- Development of a predictive model to predict the likelihood of customer retention using Python.
- Implementation of data-driven solutions, such as user experience personalization and loyalty programs. Using A/B testing to evaluate the effectiveness of the implemented solutions.
- Ongoing evaluation of results to continuously improve the customer lifecycle.

# **EDUCATION**

Stanford – Cisco Networking – AWS - IBM – Harvard – MIT 2018 - 2023 Various certificates remotely.

# **Stanford University**

2017 - 2021 Special Scholarship for: Computer Science.

#### Idat

**2016 - 2019** Peruvian State Scholarship: **Mobile Application Development**.

#### **Iberotec**

**2016 - 2019** Peruvian State Scholarship: **Web Application Development**.

#### **SKILLS**

- Languages: HTML, CSS, C#, JavaScript, Python, TypeScript.
- Frameworks: React, Vue, React Native, Express.
- Technologies: Node.Js, Nest.Js, Expo, Next.Js, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, MySQL, MongoDB, OpenCV, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Google Cloud, Azure, Git / GitHub.

#### FREELANCE / PERSONAL PROJECTS

- SV Multiplayer Village (Network & Content MOD), C#, JS, ASP.NET, Node.Js.
  Multiplayer implementation for Stardew Valley breaking the 4-user limit.
- 3PRO HOME Property Finder, Python, Scrapy, JS, React, Node.Js, PHP, MySQL. Advanced Web Scraping, obtaining massive data for further study/use/development.
- Ryzebloom (Free Tech Learn), JS, HTML, CSS, React, Node.Js, Expo, PHP, WP (CMS). Free segmented technology education platform for children, youth and adults.